<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc [
  <!ENTITY nbsp    "&#160;">
  <!ENTITY zwsp   "&#8203;">
  <!ENTITY nbhy   "&#8209;">
  <!ENTITY wj     "&#8288;">
]>
<rfc xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" submissionType="IETF" docName="draft-mangrove-workgroup-mangrove-latest" category="std" ipr="trust200902" obsoletes="" updates="" xml:lang="en" symRefs="true" sortRefs="true" tocInclude="true" version="3">
  <!-- xml2rfc v2v3 conversion 3.20.0 -->
  <front>
    <title>Mangrove: A Unified Framework for Internet Topology, Routing Abstraction, and Modeling</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-mangrove-workgroup-mangrove-latest"/>
    <author initials="Y. R." surname="Yang" fullname="Y. Richard Yang">
      <organization>Yale University</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Watson 208A, 51 Prospect Street</street>
          <street>New Haven, CT 06511</street>
          <street>United States of America</street>
        </postal>
        <email>yang.r.yang@yale.edu</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author initials="B. L." surname="Lewis" fullname="Bradley Lewis">
      <organization>Yale University</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>33 Lynwood Pl</street>
          <street>New Haven, CT 06511</street>
          <street>United States of America</street>
        </postal>
        <email>bradley.lewis@yale.edu</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author initials="D. M." surname="Mertus" fullname="Daniel Mertus">
      <organization>Yale University</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Unit 404, 367 Elm Street</street>
          <street>New Haven, CT 06511</street>
          <street>United States of America</street>
        </postal>
        <email>daniel.mertus@yale.edu</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author initials="A. S." surname="Shi" fullname="Alex Shi">
      <organization>Yale University</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>33 Lynwood Pl</street>
          <street>New Haven, CT 06511</street>
          <street>United States of America</street>
        </postal>
        <email>alex.shi@yale.edu</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author initials="J. Z." surname="Zhang" fullname="Joseph Zhang">
      <organization>Yale University</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>33 Lynwood Pl</street>
          <street>New Haven, CT 06511</street>
          <street>United States of America</street>
        </postal>
        <email>joseph.zhang@yale.edu</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="March" day="4"/>
    <workgroup>ALTO</workgroup>
    <abstract>
      <t> This document describes a novel system called Mangrove for obtaining global visibility
            across the Internet. It achieves this through constructing a comprehensive, unified
            representation of the Internet's topology and routing behavior by aggregating and
            indexing diverse data sources. he core challenge is obtaining an accurate, up-to-date
            model of how packets traverse the global Internet given the Internet's vast scale,
            dynamic nature, and fragmented visibility across multiple organizations collecting data
            in different formats.</t>
      <t>Mangrove addresses this by leveraging the hierarchical structure and natural
            abstractions of Internet architecture. It collects and integrates data from traceroute
            measurements, BGP routing tables, IP allocation records, and active broadband
            measurements. This multi-source data is partitioned and indexed across multiple
            granularity levels - geographic regions, autonomous systems, and IP prefixes - allowing
            effective storage, querying, and scalable processing.</t>
      <t>Mangrove constructs a unified topology and routing representation augmented with an
            extensible ruleset derived from Internet axioms and measured data. For arbitrary
            source-destination pairs, it computes estimated packet paths and associated performance
            metrics at the highest feasible granularity level based on available information
            completeness. The system handles real-time Internet dynamics through incremental rule
            refinement using detected changes in routing data and measurements. This enables timely
            updates to the topology model without full recomputation. Mangrove aims to provide
            researchers and operators an unprecedented unified Internet view for analysis,
            optimization, planning, security, and regulatory tasks.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <middle>
    <section anchor="sect-1" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Introduction and Motivation</name>
      <t> The Internet is a vast and complex network of interconnected devices, spanning the
            globe and enabling communication between billions of users and systems. Understanding
            the underlying topology and routing model of the Internet is crucial for researchers,
            network operators, and service providers to gain insights into routing dynamics,
            performance characteristics, and potential vulnerabilities. However, the current state
            of Internet topology and routing mapping is fragmented, with multiple organizations and
            projects collecting data through various measurement techniques, such as traceroutes,
            BGP looking glass dumps, and performance metrics. This data is often inconsistent in
            format, incomplete, and distributed across multiple sources, making it challenging to
            obtain a comprehensive and unified view of the Internet's topology. We wish to build a
            system that unifies this information into a single representation of routing and
            topology models of the Internet at different points in time, allowing for queries to be
            performed against this representation.</t>
      <t>By creating a comprehensive model of the Internet’s topology and routing dynamics, this
            system will enable a wide range of applications and analysis, including:</t>
      <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
          <t>Network monitoring/troubleshooting: The ability to detect and localize routing
            anomalies, such as loops, black holes, or performance degradation can aid in identifying
            and resolving network issues more efficiently. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Vulnerability assessment and security analysis: A unified view of the Internet's
            topology and routing can help identify potential vulnerabilities, such as single points
            of failure or routing hijacks, enabling proactive measures to enhance network security
            and resilience.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Traffic Engineering and Capacity Planning: By understanding the flow of traffic
            across the Internet, service providers can optimize resource allocation, load balancing,
            and capacity planning, improving overall network performance and efficiency.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Resilience and Disaster Recovery Planning: Modeling the impact of potential
            outages or failures on the Internet's topology and routing can inform disaster recovery
            strategies and contingency plans, ensuring business continuity and minimizing service
            disruptions.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Privacy and Regulatory Compliance Analysis: The ability to map data flows across
            the Internet can aid in identifying potential privacy violations or regulatory
            non-compliance, enabling organizations to take proactive measures to protect user data
            and comply with relevant regulations.</t>
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-2" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Problem Statement</name>
      <t>Being able to construct a digital twin of a network as large as the Internet comes with
            unique requirements for our system. These are, in no particular order:</t>
      <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
          <t>Scalability: The sheer scale of the Internet poses a significant challenge for our
            system. With over 17 billion devices connected and more than 60,000 networks or
            Autonomous Systems (ASes), each with its own internal topology, storing information
            about the paths interconnecting all these devices requires us to employ efficient
            indexing mechanisms and data structures that enable fast queries over large repositories
            of data.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Diverse Data Sources: The data required for topology mapping is scattered across
            multiple organizations, each with their own data collection methodologies, formats, and
            access methods (discussed below). The diversity of formats, from traceroute data to BGP
            table dumps, coupled with varying updating cadences and access methods, presents a
            significant challenge. Furthermore, the quality and completeness of the data can vary
            based on the vantage points of the collectors, leading to potential gaps or
            inconsistencies. Our system must be capable of integrating data from these diverse
            sources in a way that is consistent and unified.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Partial Information: Many topology measurement techniques, such as traceroutes,
            can produce incomplete or missing information due to factors like firewalls, packet
            filters, or unresponsive devices. This is often manifested as missing hops represented
            by asterisks (*) in the traceroute data. Additionally, BGP routing data lacks
            granularity below the Autonomous System (AS) level paths. IP geo-mapping databases, used
            to associate IP addresses with physical locations, also have inherent inaccuracies.
            Furthermore, performance data may be sampled or estimated statistically rather than
            being comprehensive. As such, our system must be capable of producing the best-effort
            topology and routing representation for packets between two hosts, even when the input
            data is incomplete or partially missing.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Real-time, Dynamic Updates: The Internet is a highly dynamic environment, with
            routing changes, network outages, and topology shifts occurring continuously. Events
            like outages, attacks, or policy changes can trigger changes in the routing behavior,
            with BGP convergence times ranging from seconds to minutes after an event. New links and
            nodes are constantly being added, while others are going down. Our system needs
            mechanisms to detect these relevant changes and incrementally update the topology
            representation in real-time or near real-time. However, this requirement presents a
            trade-off between the cost of performing full recomputations versus maintaining and
            applying deltas or incremental updates. Additionally, our system must meet the time
            window requirements for how current the topology view needs to be, depending on the
            specific use case or application.</t>
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-3" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Internet Structure Overview</name>
      <t> At a high level, the objective of our framework is to compute a digital twin of the
            Internet routing system, and this system is complex: </t>
      <t>The Internet is composed of several layers, each serving a distinct function: </t>
      <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
          <t>Link Layer: Governs the transfer of data between directly connected nodes. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Internet Layer: Handles logical addressing and routing of data across the network.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Transport Layer: Manages end-to-end communication and ensures reliable data
            transfer. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Application Layer: Enables network services and applications to interface with the
            underlying transport protocols. </t>
        </li>
      </ol>
      <t>Sitting on top of these layers, Autonomous Systems (ASes) and the Border Gateway
            Protocol (BGP) govern how packets traverse networks operated by different administrative
            entities. </t>
      <t>The behavior of the Internet can be characterized by two principal components: the
            underlying network topology and the routing policies enforced by the protocol ruleset.
            Network topology delineates the physical connectivity constraints that determine the
            paths packets can traverse. However, network infrastructure is in a constant state of
            flux as devices are continually added, removed, or reconfigured, posing challenges for
            comprehensive topology measurement outside an AS's purview. Routing policies dictate how
            packets are forwarded along available paths in accordance with protocol rules. Protocols
            like Equal-Cost Multi-Path (ECMP) routing introduce complexity, making the determination
            of single best paths more difficult. Furthermore, most devices do not expose their
            Forwarding Information Bases (FIBs), obscuring the precise ruleset implementations. </t>
      <t>Consequently, measurements provide the primary evidence of the effects induced by the
            combination of the underlying topology and the applied routing policies. This
            abstraction of rule systems onto physical network elements results in observable path
            properties, such as latency, bandwidth, and jitter, which are crucial for characterizing
            end-to-end packet delivery performance between nodes.</t>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-4" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Existing Systems Overview</name>
      <t>Current solutions for internet visibility topology generally divide their focuses across
            two key categories: topology and routing inference and metadata measurement.
            Additionally, these solutions further subdivide into consumer solutions and enterprise
            solutions providing a mix of both aggregate and granular data measured in varying units
            of time.</t>
      <t>Topology and routing measurement solutions employ a collection paradigm that includes:</t>
      <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
          <t>Distributed Nodes: Operated either by the organization itself or external
            contributors, these nodes form the backbone of data collection efforts. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Periodic Traceroute Measurements: Using tools such as paris traceroute,
            measurements are periodically collected between nodes to infer network topology.</t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t>Data Inference: The collected data is analyzed to infer the network topology,
            relying on the information returned by traceroute measurements.</t>
        </li>
      </ol>
      <t> Metadata measurement solutions diverge from topology measurement primarily in the
            nature of data collected. Unlike topology measurement, which focuses on the structure of
            the network, metadata measurement seeks to understand the properties of network paths.
            This requires a significantly larger dataset, typically sourced from a wide user base
            employing network measurement tools. The process involves: </t>
      <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
          <t> Connection to a Local Server: Establishing a baseline for measurement by
            connecting to a server in close proximity to the user. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t> Connection Saturation: Maximizing the use of the connection to ensure
            comprehensive data collection. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t> Measurement Execution: Performing measurements to gather data on the connection. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t> Optional Traceroute Measurement: If feasible, supplementing the measurement with
            traceroute data for enhanced insight. </t>
        </li>
        <li>
          <t> Statistical Inference: Applying statistical methods to the collected data to
            extrapolate insights on broadband measurements, with a focus on geographical
            specificity.</t>
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-5" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Mangrove: A Framework For Internet Abstraction and Modeling</name>
      <t>The existing choice between focusing on traceroute data or broadband connection
            measurements presents a significant trade-off for organizations. To generate an accurate
            topology, organizations need control: owning the network devices, collecting traceroute
            data on a consistent schedule, and sending as many traceroutes as possible in ways that
            maximize inference. However, broadband measurement requires detail and quantity:
            distributing access nodes, collecting as much consumer information as possible, using
            traceroutes as only secondary sources of information. This tradeoff in required
            infrastructure has made it difficult to bridge the gap between topology, path inference,
            and associated metadata.</t>
      <t>Topology and routing inference is done through the analysis of data retrieved from
            techniques including traceroute experiments and BGP Looking Glass dumps. This raw data
            alone provides insight into the ‘real’ structure of the Internet; traceroute
            measurements form the backbone of most existing Internet topology mapping efforts, and
            when combined with Autonomous System routing data, can be used to infer the paths that
            exist throughout the internet. The primary technique for collecting these involves
            deploying a distributed set of vantage points or measurement nodes across the Internet.
            These nodes periodically initiate traceroute experiments towards predetermined
            destination IP addresses or prefixes. Many topology mapping projects like CAIDA's Ark
            and RIPE Atlas have deployed large measurement infrastructures consisting of hundreds or
            thousands of vantage points globally. These provide diverse perspectives into Internet
            paths from different edge networks. </t>
      <t>Most existing platforms focus on either traceroute data collection and analysis, or
            BGP/routing data. Very few solutions currently attempt an integrated data fusion across
            measurements, routing, geolocation and performance data.</t>
      <t>We propose the engineering of a scalable system that aggregates and indexes data from
            various sources to construct a single, unified representation of Internet topology. This
            representation would provide researchers and network operators with rich information
            about the connectivity between devices on the Internet, augmented by performance metrics
            that could inform them about connection quality between networks. </t>
      <section anchor="sect-5-1" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Methodology</name>
        <t>To construct this unified representation, our system will leverage the natural
               abstractions offered by Internet architecture to provide the best level of estimates
               for topologies and routing decisions. The core methodology involves the following
               steps: </t>
        <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
            <t>Data Aggregation: Collect and integrate data from multiple sources, including
               CAIDA Ark traceroute measurements, BGP looking glass dumps, Regional Internet
               Registry (RIR) records, and performance data from projects like M-Lab, Ookla, and
               perfSONAR.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Abstraction: Leverage the natural abstractions in Internet architecture, such
               as the Autonomous System (AS) level, to represent topology at different
               granularities. This allows the system to handle incomplete data and provide estimates
               at varying resolutions. Represent this as a multidimensional graph where nodes can
               aggregate, inherit, or point to other nodes on the graph depending on the abstraction
               layer.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Rule Generation: Use network axioms to generate an initial set of rules for AS
               pathing using BGP dumps, traceroute first hops, and business relationships. The
               system then repeatedly generates and refines lower rule sets using axioms, AS
               pathing, FIBs, and known clustering policies for levels of resolution from subnet to
               devices.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Compression: Completed rules are grouped into sets for their particular header
               space. The system stores such classes in a tree which represents IP prefixes and
               addresses. Indexing into and moving down levels for a chosen destination determines
               the rule-set. This allows for constant-time indexing, with a slight space tradeoff.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Path Inference: For a given source and destination IP address pair, the system
               will attempt to provide the highest certainty estimate of the path a packet would
               take, based on the aggregated data and rule trie. If complete traceroute data is
               available, it will be used to provide a detailed IP-level path. If not, the system
               will attempt to construct a path using the rule set for its IP prefix and graph edge
               weights. The final fall back is to AS-level paths derived from BGP routing
               information.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Performance Enrichment: Augment the topology representation with performance
               metrics, such as bandwidth, latency, and throughput, obtained from sources like M-Lab
               and Ookla. Such data can be added by matching consumer collected traceroutes with
               those of topology measurement solutions. For AS-level paths, performance metrics can
               be averaged across nodes within each AS.</t>
          </li>
        </ol>
        <t>With the above, we will provide users with an interface that they may use to query
               the path that a packet would take between any two arbitrary source and destination IP
               addresses. Our system will leverage all of the information it has aggregated to
               provide a ‘best estimate’ of this path, while augmenting this with performance
               metrics at the highest level of resolution.</t>
        <t>To illustrate this, we consider a sample user query where a user wishes to know the
               path a packet would take between source IP address A and destination IP address B. </t>
        <t>At a high level, our system will do the following:</t>
        <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
            <t>Map each IP address to their corresponding AS numbers: the system will maintain
               an IP address to AS lookup as a result of aggregating this data from several sources
               over time. The most recent match for the IP address will be used.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Analyze BGP routing data for each corresponding AS: if the IP addresses lie in
               separate autonomous systems, we may query each of the corresponding BGP table
               representations for each AS to determine the AS path that a packet will use to get
               from A to B.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Infer AS-level Path: After determining the AS numbers for the source and
               destination IP addresses, and analyzing the BGP routing data for the corresponding
               ASes, the system can infer the AS-level path that a packet would take from the source
               AS to the destination AS. This AS-level path would be a sequence of AS numbers,
               representing the path through different Autonomous Systems.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Retrieve Traceroute Data for Each AS Hop: For each AS hop in the inferred
               AS-level path, the system will attempt to retrieve relevant traceroute data to
               reconstruct the IP-level path within that AS. This can be done by querying the
               indexed traceroute data based on the source and destination AS numbers for that
               particular hop.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Reconstruct IP-level Path Within Each AS: If traceroute data is available for
               an AS hop, the system will use that data to reconstruct the IP-level path within that
               AS.If no traceroute data is available, the system will treat that AS hop as a single
               hop in the final path, representing the AS-level transition.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Handle Missing Hops and Incomplete Paths: If there are missing hops
               (represented by *) within an AS hop, the system will group consecutive * hops and
               represent them as a single AS-level hop in the final path. If no traceroute data is
               available for an entire AS hop, the system will represent that hop at the AS-level in
               the final path. This illustrates our concept of ‘granularity’ - where there is
               missing data at a specific resolution, we may resort to using data at a lower
               resolution (the AS level) to still provide some insight into the path.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Associate Performance Metrics: The system can then associate relevant
               performance metrics, such as latency, bandwidth, or throughput, with each hop in the
               final path. In cases where our system must resort to lower resolutions, we may use
               aggregation and averaging techniques to provide a rough estimate on connectivity
               statistics for that portion of the path.</t>
          </li>
        </ol>
      </section>
      <section anchor="sect-5-2" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>System Architecture</name>
        <t>The proposed system will consist of the following key components:</t>
        <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
            <t>Data Collectors: Modules responsible for fetching and processing data from
               various sources, such as CAIDA Ark, BGP looking glass servers, RIRs, and performance
               measurement platforms. </t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Data Unification Engine: A central component that integrates and indexes the
               collected data into a unified representation, handling data format conversions,
               deduplication, and consistency checks. </t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Topology Database: A scalable and distributed data store designed to store and
               query the unified topology representation, supporting both IP-level and AS-level
               granularities. The data will be represented as a multi-dimensional graph, its
               associated rule sets in equivalence classes, and a compressed trie.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Query Engine: An engine with a custom query language that can quickly join data
               at multiple levels of resolution depending on the user request. </t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Interface: An API or user interface that allows researchers and network
               operators to submit source-destination IP pairs and retrieve the corresponding
               estimated paths, along with associated performance metrics.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>Real-time Update Handler: A component that monitors for changes in the
               underlying data sources and triggers updates to the topology representation, ensuring
               it remains current with the dynamic nature of the Internet.</t>
          </li>
        </ol>
      </section>
      <section anchor="sect-5-3" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Scalability</name>
        <t>With regards to discussion about scalabiltiy, the partitioning and distribution of
               data across different levels can be structured as follows:</t>
        <section anchor="sect-5-3-1" numbered="true" toc="default">
          <name>Geographic</name>
          <t>At the geographic level, the system can partition the data based on geographic
                  regions or clusters. This level is responsible for storing and managing the BGP
                  routing data for the Autonomous Systems (ASes) within each geographic cluster. The
                  primary function of this level is to handle AS-level path inference and resolution
                  based on the BGP routing data.</t>
        </section>
        <section anchor="sect-5-3-2" numbered="true" toc="default">
          <name>AS</name>
          <t>Within each geographic partition, the system can further partition the data by
                  individual AS. At this level, each AS is responsible for storing and managing its
                  own internal routing topology and traceroute data. This level is designed to
                  handle IP-level path reconstruction and inference within the boundaries of a
                  single AS.</t>
          <t>The AS-level partitions can maintain the following data: </t>
          <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
              <t>Internal Routing Topology: This includes the router-level topology within
                  the AS, representing the interconnections between routers and network devices. </t>
            </li>
            <li>
              <t>Traceroute Data: Traceroute measurements conducted within the AS, capturing
                  the IP-level paths between different ingress and egress points or subnets. </t>
            </li>
            <li>
              <t>Performance Metrics: Performance data (e.g., latency, bandwidth) associated
                  with links or paths within the AS, obtained from sources like M-Lab or Ookla. </t>
            </li>
          </ol>
        </section>
        <section anchor="sect-5-3-3" numbered="true" toc="default">
          <name>Subnet/Prefix</name>
          <t>To further enhance granularity and scalability, the system can introduce an
                  additional level of partitioning at the subnet or IP prefix level. This level can
                  store traceroute data and performance metrics specific to individual subnets or IP
                  prefixes within an AS. </t>
          <t>By partitioning the data at these multiple levels, the system can distribute the
                  workload and storage requirements across different components, allowing for
                  parallel processing and improved scalability. </t>
          <t>The workflow for resolving a path between a source and destination IP address
                  would involve the following steps:</t>
          <ol spacing="normal" type="1"><li>
              <t>The geographic partition responsible for the source and destination ASes is
                  identified, and the AS-level path is determined using the BGP routing data. </t>
            </li>
            <li>
              <t>For each AS hop in the inferred AS-level path, the corresponding AS
                  partition is queried to retrieve traceroute data and reconstruct the IP-level path
                  within that AS. </t>
            </li>
            <li>
              <t>If further granularity is required or available, the subnet/prefix level
                  partitions can be consulted to obtain more detailed traceroute data and
                  performance metrics for specific IP prefixes or subnets along the path. </t>
            </li>
          </ol>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-6" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>IANA Considerations</name>
      <t> This document has no actions for IANA.</t>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-7" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Security Considerations</name>
      <t> The collection, distribution of MoWIE information should consider the security
            requirements on information privacy and information integration protection and
            authentication in both sides. Since the network status is not directly related to any
            special user, there is currently no any privacy issue. But the information transmitted
            to the application can pass through a lot of middle box and can be changed by the man in
            the middle. To protect the network information, an end to end encryption and integration
            is needed. Also, the network needs to authenticate the information exposure provided to
            right applications. These security requirements can be implemented by the TLS and other
            security mechanisms. </t>
    </section>
  </middle>
  <back>
    <!-- insert references here -->
   </back>
</rfc>
